嗯。
立法會主席。
多謝，主席。
The committee wishes to affirm.
在2016至2017。
on behalf of the Public Accounts Committee.
給，實質公共資源涉及，和NGO的工作。
社會福利部門提供補貼給非政府組織，為提供福利服務在香港。
社會福利部門和公眾監察LSG撥款從價值 for money 觀點。
到香港，委員會強調，應有適當和透明的責任機制。
12.5 billion of lump sum grants/superventions were allocated to 165 NGOs.
發言，石禮謙議員就政府帳目委員會第六十九A號報告書向本會發言，石禮謙議員。
The indispensable role of NGOs in providing a wide range of services to meet the divergent need of different social strata in Hong Kong.
我有榮耀呈報我們的報告號碼69，，which contains our conclusions and recommendations on Chapter 1 of the Director's Audit Report Number 69 on administration of lump sum grants by the Social Welfare Department.
Starting from 2001, a lump sum grant, hereby known as LSG, subvention system, lump sum grant subvention system was rolled out with a view to allowing NGO management autonomy and flexibility in the deployment of subvention resources.
在這章節，歐洲委員會已審查了一些NGO未遵守WSD發出的指引，包括LSG手冊及相關財務書面，以及績效成果和標準。
threshold。
however。
Accountability to the public.
One of the exemption criteria.
appropriate follow-up measures.
委員會表達關心，關於持續。
U.D. to take a more proactive role and be alert to NGO possible financial viability issues.
stipulated in the funding and service agreement, hereby known as FSA, signed between NGO and SWD.
SWD is urged to ensure that the provision of quality services would not be affected by the NGO LSG deficits.
The social welfare department only implemented these requirements from 2009 to 2010, a delay of some six years.
The guideline require a subvented body to review and disclose annually in a review report the remunerations of its top three tiers staff, unless it meets certain exemption criteria.
In 2003, the Director of Administration issued a memorandum promulgating a set of guidelines for the control and monitoring of remuneration practices in supervisory bodies.
The committee expresses grave concern and dissatisfaction about SWD's failure to effectively monitor NGO service delivery, and strongly urged SWD to closely monitor NGOs with persistent underperformance and devise with them.
lump sum grant operating deficits incurred by some NGO, the committee considers the persistent lump sum grant deficit coupled with the depleted LSG reserve of an NGO might serve as a reminder for SW.
委員會表達對社會福利部和勞工及福利局（SWD政策局）在實施披露要求方面的不足之處感到不滿，這些要求旨在提升NGO的透明度和。
The committee also expresses grave concern about the social welfare department' lax attitude and the serious delay in seeking clarification with the administration wing and the financial services and treasury bureau on the calculation of the 50% income threshold.
personnel in Hong Kong.
構成約97段。
最後ly，我 wish to record my appreciation.
或用一個適當的基礎為解僱。
details of the committee's conclusion and recommendations are set in the report.
of the contribution made by members of the committee, particularly the lead member.
作為行政已經成立了一個專責小組，來審視增強累進補助金系統。
And offer advice to them in timely manner, taking into account actual circumstances of individual NGOs.
社會福利部門是強烈 urge，要 take 一個更 proactive 領 lead， to address the problem of staff turnover。
委員會考慮到，而家雖然重要，對於NGO嚟講，要遵守關於使用臨時撥款的指引。
SWD should enhance in communication with those NGO which have encountered genuine difficulties in apportioning process.
委員會表達關切，一些NGO未將辦公室開支分攤給非FSA活動。
The committee recommends the taskforce to take into consideration a host of issues, such as engaging different stakeholders, including frontline staff, in taking forward the review.
The report has touched upon issues relating to governance and management of NGO and and the management of conflicts of interest by the LSG Independent Complaints Handling Committee.
SWD's calculation of the 50% income threshold deviated from the intent of the memorandum, which resulted in fewer NGOs required to disclose their senior staff imunimunurations.
Pointing out that people are the most valuable assets of NGOs in providing quality service, the committee expresses grave concern and dissatisfaction about social welfare's slow and inadequate actions to tackle the problem of high turnover of social work.
Mr. Lam。
政府法案首讀。
二零一八年税務修訂第三號。
Our gratitude also goes to the witnesses who attended the hearings held by the committee.
I would like to express our gratitude to the Director of Audit and his colleagues for their unfailing support, and lastly, but not the least, to our Secretary for their hard work. Thank you, Mr. President.